Guide to the Ray Lyman Wilbur, President of Stanford University, Papers SC0064A
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ray Lyman Wilbur, president of Stanford University, papers
1914-1951
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman)
SC0064A
172.5 Linear Feet
Administrative files from the president's office. The material dates primarily from the administration of Ray Lyman Wilbur, but the last boxes extend into the terms of Presidents Tresidder and Sterling. Included is correspondence relating to administrative, financial, and educational affairs at Stanford, particularly as relates to departments and schools, athletics, organizations, buildings, clubs, individuals, and the Stanford Medical School.
Biographical/Historical note
Ray Lyman Wilbur graduated from Stanford University (B.S.1896, M.S. 1897) and from Cooper Medical College (M.D. 1899). He served as lecturer and professor of physiology and of medicine (1897-1903), Dean of the Cooper Medical College (Stanford) (1911-1916), third President of Stanford University (1916-1943), Chancellor of Stanford University, and Secretary of the Interior (September 1929-1933) under President Hoover.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
The records were transferred from the President's Office in 1965.
Biography
Ray Lyman Wilbur graduated from Stanford University (B.S. 1896, M.S. 1897) and from Cooper Medical College (M.D. 1899). He served as lecturer and professor of physiology and of medicine (1897-1903), Dean of the Cooper Medical College (Stanford)(1911-1916), third President of Stanford University (1916-1943), Chancellor of Stanford University, and Secretary of the Interior (September 1929-1933) under President Hoover.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of administrative files from the President's Office. The material dates primarily from the administration of Ray Lyman Wilbur, but the last boxes extend into the terms of Presidents Tresidder and Sterling. Included is correspondence relating to administrative, financial, and educational affairs at Stanford, particularly as relates to departments and schools, athletics, organizations, buildings, clubs, individuals, and the Stanford Medical School. The student organizations represented in the collection include Glee Club, Rifle Club, Cosmopolitan Club, Dramatic Council, Flying Club, Chapparal, the Men's Council, the Women's Council, the YMCA, the YWCA, and the ASSU. Other folders of note include Board of Athletic Control, Branner Seismometer Station, Dean of Men, Dean of Women, Defense (various civilian defense issues during World War II), Military Science, and Military Training (on campus during World War I).
Arrangement
The papers are arranged chronologically by academic year and then alphabetically by folder title.
Bennett, John E.; Zinser, Hans.; Wittman, Joseph van Beuren.; Townley, S. D.; Fuller, W. Palmer.; Sterling, J. E. Wallace (John Ewart Wallace); Stanford University -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Spragens, Thomas A.; Sloss, Leon.; Shedd, Margaret,; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman); Rice, Jack.; Reynolds, Ralph.; Newhall, W. Mayo.; Jordan, David Starr; Manspeaker, Alfred F.; Morgan, Percy T.; Tresidder, Donald Bertrand; Jones, Josephine.; Hopkins, Timothy.; Jacobson, David S.; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922; Stanford University. Office of the President; Hodgson, Caspar.; Faust, Clarence H. (Clarence Henry); Spragens, Thomas A.; Townley, S. D.; Evans, Samuel A.; Cubberley, Ellwood Patterson; Eells, Charles P.; Walker, Frank Fish; Davis, Horace; Crary, Gordon R.; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman); Luce, Henry R. (Henry Robinson); Crary, Allan R.; Manspeaker, Alfred F.; Morgan, Percy T.; Cross, Harold H. U.; Cutler, Leland W.; Reynolds, Ralph; Rice, Jack; Ditz, George A.; Shedd, Margaret Cochran; Hoover, Herbert; Sloss, Leon; Stanford, Josiah Winslow; Hodgson, Caspar; Arnold, Ralph.; Berner, Bertha.; Jacobson, David S.; Bennett, John E.; Jones, Josephine; Castle, Otis.; Jordan, Jessie Knight; Cutler, Leland W.; Hopkins, Timothy; Ditz, George A.; Durand, William Frederick; Eells, Charles P.; Evans, Samuel A.; Eurich, Alvin C. (Alvin Christian); Crary, Allan R.; Cross, Harold H. U.; Stanford, Thomas Welton; Crary, Gordon R.; Crothers, George E. (George Edward)
- 1915-1917, Series 1
  - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic Council, 1914-1916 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Academic Secretary (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Admissions, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Admissions of Women (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Board, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Association, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Association, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Academy of Medicine (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Ambulance Corps, 1916-17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Ambulance Corps, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Ambulance Field Service, 1916-17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science; American Association of Pathology and Bacteriology, 1916-17 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineers (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American League of California, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Medical Association, 1916-17 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Social Hygiene Association, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Anatomy, 1916-17 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Vivisection, 1916-17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Applications for Positions, 1915-16 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Applications for Positions, 1916-17 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Applications (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Applied Biology, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Applied Mathematics, 1916-17 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Appointments Secretary, 1915-16 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Appointments - genito-urinary (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Appointments - pediatrics, 1914-15 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Arboretum, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Arnold, Ralph, 1915-17 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Art, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Assembly Hall, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Assistants, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Assistants, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Associated Press (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Associated Students, 1916-17 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Association of American Colleges (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Association of American Universities (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Association of University Professors (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Athletics, 1915-17 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Automobiles, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Auxiliary Stanford Clinics, 1916-17 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - B, 1915-16 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - B, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - B, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - B, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bacteriology, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bassett, L. E., 1915-1916 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Belgian Relief, 1916-17 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bennett, John E., 1916 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bentley, Prof. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bentley, Prof. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Berner, Bertha, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Board of Athletic Control (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bohemian Club, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Botany, 1916-17 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Boy Scouts, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Branner, J. C., 1915-16 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Buckel Foundation (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Budget - Anatomy (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Building Needs (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Building Needs, Dept. of Education (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Business Manager (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Business Office, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - C, 1916 Jan- Dec (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - C, 1916 May - 1915 Nov (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - C, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - California, Univ. Of (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - California Academy of Medicine, 1916-17 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - U.C. Berkeley, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - California Board of Education; California Board of Medical Examiners, 1916-17 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - California Society for the Promotion of Medical Research, 1916-17 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - California State Medical Society and Calvert Museum (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Castle, Otis, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chaparral, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chemistry, 1915-17 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cheating Commission Report, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Christian Science Society, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Church Chimes, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Circular letters, 1916-17 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Civil Engineering (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Class of 1896 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Coffin Research Fund (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Colliver, J. A. - correspondence (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Graduate Study (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Literary Contests, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Practice Teaching, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Schedules and Examinations (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Committee on Scholarships, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Commonwealth Club, 1915-16 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Commonwealth Club, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Continuous Session (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Cosmopolitan Club, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Cranks, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Cross, Harold H. U., 1916 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Cubberley, E., 1916 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - D, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - D, 1916-17 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Davis, Horace, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dean of Women; Dentistry, 1916-17 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Department of Executives; Department Meeting Notices; Diplomatic Training, 1916-17 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dormitories (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - E, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - E, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Economics, 1915-17 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Education, 1915-17 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Educational Aid Society, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Eells, Charles P., 1916 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Electrical Engineering, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Elocution (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Encina Gym (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Endowment Suggestions, 1916-17 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - English, 1916-17 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Entomology and Bionomics (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Engagements (passed) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - European Universities (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - F, 1916-17 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Organization, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fellowships, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Flugel Dictionary (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Founder's Day, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Forum (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Four-Quarter System, 1916-17 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Fraternities, 1916-17 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - G, 1915-16 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - G, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - General Education Board, 1914-16 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - General Interest (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Geology and Mining, 1916-17 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - German, 1916-17 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Gifts (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Girl's Clubs (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Golf Club, 1916-17 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Study, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Graduate Study Committee, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Grant, J. D., 1916 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Graphic Arts (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Greek, 1916-17 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Grounds lease on campus (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Gymnasium, Encina, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Gymnasium, Roble, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - H, 1913, 1915, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - H, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - H, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Hilmer, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - History, 1916-17 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hodgson, Caspar, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Home Economics, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Honor System, 1916-17 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hooper Foundation (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hopkins, Timothy, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hospital (New) Equipment, etc. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hygiene (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - I, 1916-17 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Illinois University (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Inaugural (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Incinerator (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Indian Board of Cooperation, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Inheritance Tax, 1916-17 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Installation as President Ray Lyman Wilbur, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Intercollegiate Intelligence Bureau, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Interior, Department of, Bureau of Education, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Invitations to speak, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - J, 1916-17 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Japan, Relations with (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Japanese-American Daily News (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Governor Johnson (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Jordan, D. S., 1914-15 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Jordan, D. S., 1916-17 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Journalism, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Junior College, 1916-17 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - K, 196-17 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Kellogg, salary (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - L, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - L, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Latin, 1916-17 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Law, 1916-17 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Leach C. N. (Dr.) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Leaves (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Legislation, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Library, 1916-17 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Literary Contests Commission (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Los Angeles Chautauqua Association, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - M, general, Dec. 1915 - Feb. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - M, general, Mar. - Apr. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - M, general, May - June 1916 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - M, general, July - Dec. 1916 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - M, general, Jan. - Mar. 1917 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - M, general, Apr. - July 1917 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Marine Corps, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Marine Laboratory, 1916-17 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Mathematics, 1916-17 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Medical Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Medical Education, 1916-17 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Medical School, Jan. - May, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Medical School, June - July, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Medical School, Aug. 1916 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Medical School, Sept. 1916 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Medical School, Oct. 1916 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Medical School, Nov. - Dec. 1916 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Medical School, Jan. 1917 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Medical School, Feb. 1917 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Medical School, Mar. 1917 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Medical School, Apr. 1917 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Medical School, May - June 1917 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Medical School, July 1917 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Medical School, Anatomy (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Medical School, Animal Room, 1915-16 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Medical School, Appointments - general, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Medical School, Appointments - Bacteriology (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Medical School, Appointments - Genito-Urinary Clinic (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Medical School, Appointments - Obstetrics and Gynecology, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Medical School, Appointments - Orthopedics (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Medical School, Appointments - Pediatrics (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Medical School, Appointments - Surgery (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Medical School, Bacteriology, 1913-14 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Medical School, Bacteriology, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Medical School, Bacteriology, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Medical School, J. C. Branner (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Medical School, Budget, 1915-17 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Medical School, Cathcart's address on the University and the Professional School (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Medical School, Children's Hospital (Dr. Adelaide Brown) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Medical School, Endowments (Gonzales, Rank and Loesser) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Medical School, Felton and Neilson Acts, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Medical School, General Education Board (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Medical School, House Rentals - Campus (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Medical School, Jordan Scholarship, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Medical School, Lane Hospital, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Medical School, Lane Lectures, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Medical School, Medicine (Division) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Medical School, Miscellaneous, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Medical School, New Hospital (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Medical School, Obstetrics and Gynecology (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Medical School, Pediatrics, 1915-17 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Medical School, Physician Superintendent, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Medical School, Plans to convert portions of the Museum Building, 1914-15 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Medical School, Polyclinic (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Medical School, Problems (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Medical School, San Francisco Polyclinic (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Medical School, Surgery, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Medical School, X-Ray (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Memorial Church, 1916-17 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Memorial Committee (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Metallurgy, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Military Science: General, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Military Training, Mar. - Aug. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Military Training, Sept. - Oct. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Military Training, Nov. - Dec. 1916 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Military Training, Jan. - Mar. 1917 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Military Training, Apr. 1917 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Military Training, May 1917 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Military Training, June - July 1917 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Mills College, 1916-17 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Minnesota, University of, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Minnesota, University of, Medical School, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Morgan, Percy T., 1916 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Moulton, C. W., 1916 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Museum, 1916-17 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Museum changes (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - N, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - N, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - National Association for the Study and Education of Exceptional Children (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - National Education Association (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - National Research Council, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - National Security League, 1916-17 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - National University, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Newhall, W. Mayo, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - O, 1916-17 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Oakland Advisory Board, 1917 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Overcrowding in Departments, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - P, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - P, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - P, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - P, 1917 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Pacific Grove (Hopkins Marine Station), 1916 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Pathology (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Pellissier Memorial Fund, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Peninsular Hospital (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Permanent Blind Relief War Fund, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Physical Education (1916); Physical Education - Women (1916); Physical Training -Encina (1916-17); Physical Training - Roble (1917), 1916-1917 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Physics (1916-17); Physiology (1914-16), 1914-1917 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Poliomyelitis; Political and Social Science, Chair; Polyclinic (SF); President's House and Memoranda, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Proposed book for new students (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Psychology, 1916-17 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Public Entertainment Committee; Public Exercises (1916); Public Health (1916); Public Health Committee (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Publications - University Series; Publicity (1916); Putnam, T. M. (1916) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Q; R, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - R, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Registrar, 1916-17 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Research: Replies to Questionnaires I & II (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Richards (Dr.) correspondence; Roble Gym; Rockefeller Foundation; Romanic Languages (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - S, 1915-16 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - S, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - S, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - S, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - S, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - San Jose Chamber of Commerce (1916); Secretary (1916); Senior Play Committee (1917), 1916-1917 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Simplified Spelling; Slater, H. H. (1916); Sloss, Leon (1916); Snow, (Dr. ) Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Social Insurance Commission (1916); Social Service Board; Somers, G. B.; Spanish (1916) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Special Students; Stanford Alumnus; Stanford, J. W. (1916); Stanford Glee Club, Los Angeles (1916) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Glee Club (1916); Stanford Union; Staniford, Paul; Stillman (1917); Street, Arthur I. (1916); Student Adviser (1916), 1916-1917 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Students, Limitation of; Students (men), Limitation of; Student self-government (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Student's Insurance Plan (1916); Sutton, James (1916); Swimming Tank (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - T, 1916 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - T, 1916 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - T, 1917 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Teaching Assistants (1916); Telegrams (1917); Texas (University of); Townley, S. D. (1916); Traffic East of Quad, 1916-1917 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Trustees (1917); U (1916-17); Union High School, 1916-1917 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Union High School (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Unique, 1914-1916 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - University Matters; University Press (1916); V (1916-17), 1916-1917 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - W, 1916 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - W, 1916 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Washington University (Dedication of Bldg.); Wheeler, Benjamin Ide, (1916); Widow's Fund Insurance; Women's Club House; X-Rays; Y (1916); YMCA and YWCA (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Zinser, Hans (1916); Zoology (1916) (Box 18, Folder 13)
- 1917-1918, Series 2
  - A; Alumni (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Anatomy Department; Applied Mathematics (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Assistants; Athletics; Ba (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Bacteriology, 1917 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Bacteriology, 1918 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Be - Bi; Bl - Bo; Botany; Budget (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Br - By; Ca - Cl (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - California, Univ. Of (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Chemistry (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Civil Engineering (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Co - Cy (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Commencement (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - D (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Dean of Women (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Dormitory (Women) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - E (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Economics, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Economics, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Education (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Electrical Engineering (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - English, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - English, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Entomology; Fraternities (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Ga - Gr; Geology and Mining (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - German (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Greek; Go - Gy; Graduation, Commission on, (1919-1943) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Ha - Hi (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - History (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Home Economics; Hu - Hy (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - I; Income Tax; Intercollegiate Intelligence Bureau (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Invitations to Speak (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - J (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Ka - Ky (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - La - Ll; Latin Department (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Law Department (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Library (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Lo - Ly (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Ma - Mc (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Major-Department System (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Marine Laboratory - Pacific Grove; Mathematics (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Me - Mi (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Engineering and Military Science, tactics (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Medical School, 1917 Aug. - Sept. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Medical School, 1917 Oct. - Nov. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Medical School, 1917 Dec. - 1918 Jan. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Medical School, 1918 Feb-Mar (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Medical School, 1918 Apr (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Medical School, 1918 May (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Medical School, 1918 June (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Medical School, 1918 July (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Medical School, 1918 Aug (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Medical School, Felton Acct., 1917-1918 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Mechanical Engineering (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Church; Mills College and Jessica Wilbur (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Museum (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Mo - My (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - N (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Noble Prize; Nurses (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - O (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - P (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Polyclinic (1916); Philosophy; Physics (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Physical Training (Encina); Physical Training (Roble) (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Physiology; President's House (Box 23, Folder 11)